## **SUDHANSU SEKHAR PANDA**

E-mail: <u>sudhansupanda89@gmail.com</u>

Mobile: +91-9040972072

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

To build a professional career with a reputed organization that will utilize my management & administrative skills to benefit mutual growth and success.

### **EXPERIENCE DETAILS**

Currently working as Assistant Manager in NSDL e-Governance Infrastructure

Duration: 13 Aug 2017 to till date

### **Overview of NSDL e-Governance Infrastructure Ltd**

NSDL e-Governance Infrastructure Limited (NSDL e-Gov) was originally setup as a Depository in 1995 and has over the years gained varied experience and expertise in areas that help Governments overcome the various challenges faced by them in fulfilling their core responsibilities of delivering public services to the society. NSDL e-Gov works closely with various Government agencies for designing, managing and implementing e-Governance Projects. NSDL e-Gov has also established Service Centre networks across the country which serves as access points for the general public and is efficiently used by Governments to deliver quality services in a user friendly and transparent manner to the citizens.

### **Key Responsibilities:**

Department: UID Operations

Team size: 12

Services Offered: Aadhaar Authentication, e-Kyc and e-Sign.

Working with Business Operation team various responsibilities includes:

- Registration of New Institutions into the system under various services.
- o Evaluate and Process the documents provided by the institutions for registration.
- Coordinating with internal technical team and newly registered institution for technical integration & mapping of DSC for e-sign platform.
- Prepare and maintain the daily, weekly and Monthly MIS (AUA & e-Kyc) for the management.
- Gather, consolidate and prepare the utilization report and sending to each client.
- Prepare and provide the transaction logs to each client registered for AUA & e-Kyc services.

- Prepare and verifying the proforma and tax invoices related to AUA, e-Kyc and e-sign.
- Marketing of different services offered under UID operations department over call, email and meetings with client.
- Drafting proposals for perspective clients and arranging meetings for them.
- Coordinating with UIDAI under different regions for providing information about newly registered institutions for Aadhaar Operations and closing of Centers.
- Coordinating clients for any queries and informing them about any changes made by UIDAI.
- Updating internal inspection team about addition and deletion of new agencies.
- o Evaluating the current operational strategies and recommend improvements.
- Work closely with the management for acquiring and developing new projects.
- o Involved in handling the Grievances of Enrollment Agencies.
- 2 year experience as **Marketing and Communication Executive** in Smaart Water, Worli, Mumbai

Duration: 13 Jul 2015 to 30 Jul 2017.

# **Key Responsibilities:**

# Marketing & Communication:

- Develop appropriate paper and web based Marketing & Communication plan.
- Assist in planning of marketing activities.
- Email Marketing campaign: Working in ESP-Mail chimp to design and launch email campaigns.
- o Building Social media Presence.
- Work closely with Design team to finalize Annual Campaign plan and execution and also for managing marketing collaterals like brochures, pamphlets.
- Building and maintaining appropriate customer database.
- To expand customer base by generating leads through Email campaign, Exhibitions, internet research etc.
- o Participate in conferences and exhibitions to promote products and services.
- Coordinates with vendors for exhibition work.
- Develop customer feedback loop working closely with sales and corporate services including after sales service.
- Provide regular communication to clients and prospective clients through various touch points
- o Preparing proposals for clients as per customer requirement.
- Preparing required documentations and presentations for the company.
- Monitor timely execution of every work order from procurement of materials to installation of product.
- o To identify the need for improved office procedures.

### IT works:

- Maintaining Company domain.
- o Coordinating with the web designer for any changes required in website.
- Creating email id for new employee.
- o Resolving the software related issues.
- 1.5 year experience as **Marketing Executive** in Web Station, Bhubaneswar (Odisha).

Duration: 8th Aug 2011 to 25th Feb 2013

## **Key Responsibilities:**

- Marketing company software products.
- Manage content of marketing sections of websites.
- o Plan and implement software product launch.
- Develop marketing collateral and sales tool like brochures, datasheet, presentations and proposal.
- Online marketing.
- Cold calling.
- Supporting the marketing manager and other colleagues.
- Part time worked as a SEO Executive in Auroin Infotech, Bhubaneswar.

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

- 2013-15 : M.B.A (Marketing and Operation Management) from Institute of Business and Computer Studies, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan University with a CGPA of 8.36.
- 2007-11 : B.Tech.(Computer science) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT), Odisha with an aggregate CGPA of 7.22
- 2006 : 12th (Science) from Kendriya Vidyalaya Balasore Odisha (Board-CBSE), with an aggregate of 58%.
- 2004 : 10th from Kendriya Vidyalaya Balasore Odisha (Board-CBSE), with an aggregate of 72%.

## MBA -INTERNSHIP/ ACADEMICS PROJECT:-

• Summer internship in OMFED Dairy Balasore, Odisha from 1st Jun 2014 to 15th Jul 2014.

**Topic-** "To understand Sales and Consumption Pattern of OMFED & Improving Efficiency of Supply Chain"

## **Summary:**

The research was conducted in order to identify and analyze the daily sales and consumption of OMFED milk and to investigate the market potential of OMFED dairy product, so as to improve the efficiency of supply chain management.

### **B.TECH TRAINING/ACADEMICS PROJECT:-**

A Major project on Mass e-mail dispatcher system using Java in 8th Semester.

## **Training Undertaken:**

Inter-process communication using visual C++, during summer training undergone at Directorate of Computer & Data Processing Department, Integrated Test Range, Chandipur (DRDO) Balasore (ODISHA), under the guidance of Mr.D.Pattnaik (Scientist-E).

### IT PROFICIENCY

Language: PHP, CMS: Joomla

Graphics Application: HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

• Database: My SQL

MS-office : MS Excel, MS Word

• O/S: Windows 98, 2000, XP, Vista, Windows 7 and Windows 8

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Participated in NIPM business quiz conducted by National Institute of personnel Management (Utkal Chapter) Bhubaneswar.
- Participated in seminar conducted by Madhusudan Institute of Co-operative management, Bhubaneswar.

### **COMPETENCIES**

- Leadership quality.
- Good presentation skills
- Active listener
- Communication skill and customer handling skills
- Time management skills

### **LEISURE INTERESTS**

Internet surfing, Photography, creative cooking, Listening to music.

### **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Name :- Sudhansu Sekhar Panda
 Father's Name :- Dhirendra Kumar Panda

Sex :- Male
Marital Status :- Married
Nationality :- Indian
Date of birth :- 30-07-1989

Languages Known :- English, Hindi, Oriya & Bengali

• Passport Details :- Passport no : J1435890,

Date of Issue: 23rd August 2011, Date of Expiry: 22nd August 2021

• Present Address :- C/O- Mr. Milind Maruti Kambli

D-19, 2<sup>nd</sup> Floor, Airoli, Sector-3, Near Hotel Mudra, Navi Mumbai

Maharashtra, Pin-400708

• Permanent Address :- S/O- Dhirendra Kumar Panda

AT-Fakir Mohan Nagar (Karanjia), Behind Govt. I.T.I, PO/DIST-Balasore,

Odisha, Pin-756001

## **DECLARATION**

I do here by declare that the particulars of information's and facts stated here in above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

PLACE: - Mumbai	(	

DATE: - Sudhansu Sekhar Panda